<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>※</title>
    <link>https://andrewannex.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ※</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 16:53:33 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewannex.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Moody and Circ</title>
      <link>https://andrewannex.github.io/moody-and-circ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 16:53:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewannex.github.io/moody-and-circ/</guid>
      <description>Although SpiceyPy is my largest public python package, this blog post will be about two smaller, but conceptually important projects that I have started that I think present some interesting concepts for the planetary science community.
Both of these tools are Command Line Interfaces (CLIs) that are built upon the excellent python package &amp;ldquo;python-fire&amp;rdquo;. Fire is able to produce a rich command line utility from the existing functions in a python file or class, with essentially no additional code other than the import for fire and a single function call.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://andrewannex.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 16:14:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewannex.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>About me Andrew Annex is a graduate of The University of Virginia, class of 2014. He then worked as a software engineer for two years before starting at a PhD program in Earth and Planetary Sciences at The Johns Hopkins University in the fall of 2016.
At Johns Hopkins, Andrew is researching surface processes on the planet Mars with an interest in applying machine learning to help out.
Andrew is the author of the SpiceyPy python package which wraps the NASA SPICE library for python users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First</title>
      <link>https://andrewannex.github.io/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 00:30:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewannex.github.io/first/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! I will be adding more content here about my studies and research over the next few weeks and months.
thanks for reading. -A</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>